ILGWU. Jay Mazur papers, 5780/203
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject files
  - United Farm Workers of America, 1986-1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Statement by Mazur at rally for United Farmworkers, October 28, 1986; letters to Mazur thanking him for participating in UFW events and grape boycott, including letters from UFW president Ceasr Chavez re fast; program and related correspondence for Cesar Chavez memorial service, 1993; letter to Mazur describing new contracts, October 1995; letter to Mazur announcing election victory with Bear Creek Productions, January 3, 1995; letter from UFW president Arturo Rodriguez to Michael Babcock, president, Leslie Fay Companies, urging him to keep 2,000 apparel jobs in Northeast Pennsylvania rather than export them out of U.S., threatening boycott, with cover letter to Mazur, May 12, 1994; memo to Rodriguez from attorney Marcus Camacho, litigation status report re Bruce Church Inc. v. United Farm Workers over boycott, February 18, 1994; letter to Mazur from Coco-Cola Foods re sale of Minute Maid Groves to a company bring formed by Bariston Associates, assuring him that workers will be paid the same, December 17, 1993; letter from Rodriguez to Teamsters president Ron Carey re representation dispute with Coastal Vinyards, February 4, 1994
  - United Farm Workers of America, 1983-1988 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Letter to Mazur from United Farm Workers president Cesar Chavez asking that he order and distribute copies of video, "The Wrath of Grapes," to ILGWU affiliates, June 28, 1988; letter to Mazur from Chavez inviting him to be a sponsor of event honoring California Federation of Labor president Jack Henning and 25th anniversary of union, March 4, 1987; letter from Chavez thanking ILGWU for financial contribution, with attached ad tearsheet for grape boycott, March 27, 1987; memo from Mazur to all NYC managers urging support of grape boycott, organizing picket lines at supermarkets, November 20, 1986; letter to Mazur from Chavez thanking him for helping launch boycott of A&P, Food Emporium, and Shopwell supermarkets, noting media coverage of picket line, November 24, 1986; letter to Mazur from Irv Hershenbaum, national representative of UFW, inviting him to meeting with Rep. Charles Schumer to try to dissuade him of his support for "guest worker" program, part of the Simpson-Mazzoli Immigration bill, with attached newspaper clippings, February 10, 1986; biographical sketch of Chavez; press release, "Cesar Chavez Blasts Deukmejian in Address to Massachusetts Lawmakers, Meetings with Gov. Dukakis, Mayor Flynn; Hammers at California Governor in Harvard Law School Speech Tonight," February 28, 1985, with attached excerpts from speech, prition to the Agricultural Labor Relations Board, press clippings, with cover note, "The Case against Deukmejian for Shutting Down Enforcement of Farm Labor Law"; press release, "Cesar Chavez Organizes to Make Grape Boycott of '60s & '70s Work in 1980s," June 1985; copy of United Farm Workers Food and Justice, April/May 1985; survey results re favorable perceptions of farm workers toward union, and press release from Indiana University-Purdue University at Indianapolis, January 12, 1985; newspaper clippings, 1983-85, with cover note, "What Scientific Surveys Say about Support for the UFW among Farm Workers and the Public"
  - United Federation of Teachers, Feldman, Sandra, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    See also Center for Labor-Management Policy Studies Memo from Mazur to ILGWU vp Susan Cowell and Ron Carver re meeting with Feldman for Fasanella Project, August 1, 1990
  - United Feminist Action Campaign, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Letter from ILGWU asst president Gus Tyler to Molly Yard, United Feminist Action Campaign, asking to set a meeting to introduce Yard to ILGWU women to form a bridge between the feminists of NOW (National Organization for Women) and traditional worker constituencies, August 11, 1987
  - United Food and Commerical Workers, 1986-1990 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Letter re Marval Poultry Co./Rocco Turkeys (W. Va.) strike/boycott, with attached ads, October 1986; letter from Mazur thanking union for support of ILGWU efforts to pass Textile and Apparel Trade Act, October 7, 1988; letter from Mazur to William Wynn, president, UFCW, re Weirmar Manufacturing Corp. and its runaway shop, H&B Distribution Corp. (Keasbey, NJ), with whom UFCW had a collective bargaining agreement, asking for help in resolving matter, May 5, 1988; faxed letter to ILGWU from Department Store Employees Union Local 1100, chartered by UFCW, asking for letters of support in negotiations with Macy's, April 28, 1990
  - United Furniture Workers of America, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Copy of merger agreement with International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Technical, Salaried and Machine Workers (IUE), with cover letters from attorneys to Mazur and William Bywater, president, IUE, March-August 1988
  - United Garment Workers, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Labor Organization Annual Report to Department of Labor
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Letterhead with list of affiliates; letter from AFL-CIO re request for waiving per capita tax, April 6, 1989; letter to Mazur from Sidney Davidson, president and financial secretary of United Hebrew Trades, thanking him for contribution enabling them to pay per capita tax, December 13, 1989
  - United Housing Foundation, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - United Housing Foundation, 1992-1995 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Executive Director's Report, January 4, 1994, primarily about CATCH program; resolution re restated retirement plan, signed by Mazur January 6, 1993; notice to Mazur re meeting of Board of Directors, May 13, 1993; minutes of special meetings of the Board of Directors held on October 16, 1992, and May 1, 1995; draft memo to Board of Directors from executive director re CATCH program, October 2, 1992; fax to Board of Directors from executive director noting previous memo was a draft, with attached final memo, October 13, 1992; letter to Mazur from executive director re providing grant of $60,000 for services for older residents of the United Jewish Appeal–Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York Grand Street cooperatives and Amalgamated Warbasse, December 3, 1992; financial statement for years ending December 31, 1991 and 1990, with cover letter to Mazur, June 4, 1992
  - United Housing Foundation- Affordable Housing Forum, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    See also Speeches – United Housing Foundation 1992 Letter from Mazur and Jack Sheinkman (president, ACTWU) to several members of Congress, inviting them to National Housing Policy Forum, March 19, 1992; list of invited congressional speakers and summary of their proposed legislation, March 26, 1992; briefing materials (agenda, policy recommendations), May 13, 1992; drafts of remarks to forum by Mazur; Statement of Sen. Harris Wofford to United Housing Foundation National Housing Policy Forum, May 7, 1992; Report on the National Housing Policy Forum: "Creating Affordable Housing in a Time of Crisis," May 7, 1992
  - United Housing Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    "Mutual Housing for Distressed Properties," n.d. (January 8, 1991?); minutes of meetings of Board of Directors, October 9, 1990, January 7, 1991, September 10, 1991, and meeting of Board of Directors of Community Services, Inc., September 10, 1991; financial statements for years ended December 31, 1990 and 1989, and 1989 and 1988; memo to Mazur from ILGWU vp Susan Cowell re role of UHF as catalyst for union pension-backed subsidized housing, December 1, 1991; settlement agreement with Riverbay Corporation (Co-op City), July 24, 1990; related legal correspondence (Abrams v. Community Services, Inc.), 1989-September 1990; memo from attorney re proposals for construction loan fund for Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperatives (BEC) and its nonprofit housing development corporation, New Communities, Inc., April 13, 1989; correspondence re induction of UHF president Harold Ostroff into the Cooperative Hall of Fame, November-December 1989; minutes of October 28, 1988, joint meeting of Boards of Directors of United Housing Foundation and its subsidiary, Community Services, Inc.; newspaper clippings
  - United Housing Foundation, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    Restated retirement plan actuarial valuation as of January 1, 1988; financial statements for years ended December 31, 1987 and 1986; legal decision denying summary judgment in Co-op City litigation, Abrams v. Community Services Inc., November 2, 1988; letter to Mazur from Mutual Redevelopment Houses re desire to renegotiate mortgage, November 4, 1986, with cover memo from ILGWU secretary/treasurer Irwin Solomon and related correspondence, December 3, 1986; personal and confidential proposal to UHF and Jack Sheinkman (president, ACTWU) for UHF to participate in Brooklyn Ecumenical Cooperative's Housing Rehabilitation Program, August 11, 1988
  - United Mine Workers of America, 1989-1994 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    Letter from Mazur to the postmaster general urging the issuance of a commemorative stamp honoring labor leader John. L. Lewis on the 100th anniversary of the United Mine Workers, March 7, 1989; letter to Mazur from UMWA president Richard Trumka urging him to lobby the U.S. Postal Service in support of a stamp honoring Lewis, with attached ad and biographical sketch; letter from Mazur to Trumka thanking him for help in lobbying for the Textile and Apparel Trade Act, October 10, 1988; letter from Mazur to Trumka seeking financial contribution for a rally by the Coalition of Labor Union Women in support of child care and family leave, June 22, 1987; letters to Mazur from Trumka updating him on progress of various UMWA negotiations, strikes, and other campaigns with coal mine operators (Pittston, Decker, Big Horn); memos to Mazur from ILGWU exec asst James Parrott re support activities for Pittston campaign, July-August, 1989; fundraising letter sent to NYC labor leaders by the NYC Emergency Committee in Solidarity with the UMWA, signed by Mazur and others in support of Pittston campaign, September 7,1989; memo to ILGWU NYC education directors reporting on rally to Pittston corporate headquarters in Greenwich, CT, also attended by NYNEX and Eastern Airlines strikers, October 6, 1989; Pittston campaign publicity materials; bumper sticker; newspaper clippings; handwritten notes
  - United Mine Workers of America-Coal Commission Report, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    Coal Commission Report, Secretary of Labor's Commission on United Mine Workers of America Retiree Health Benefits, November 1990; cover letter to Mazur from UMWA president Richard Trumka describing the report, sent to Secretary of Labor Elizabeth Dole by the advisory commission, November 9, 1990
  - United Mine Workers, Solidarity, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    Presentation to the Strategic Approaches Committee, AFL-CIO Executive Council winter meeting, February 1993, re update on contract discussions with various mine operators
  - United Nations Association of the United States of America (UNA-USA), 1986-1992 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    See also Economic Policy Council Agenda of annual Board of Directors meeting of December 2, 1986, with background reading including report of 1986 program activities; letter to members of the Economic Policy Council re search for replacement for Dan Burton as Executive Director; update on activities, October 1992; invitation to conference on NAFTA, with attached agenda, April 12, 1993
  - United Neighborhood Houses of New York, INC., 1992 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    Information packet re settlement house program, with cover letter to Mazur, April 14, 1992
  - United Senior Action Day, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - United Senior Action Day, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1993 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    Draft of letter (by Gus Tyler with cover memo from Herman Starobin to Mazur) noting objections by labor to current U.S. trade policy, November 30, 1993
  - United Steelworkers of America, 1986-1997 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    Letter to Mazur from United Steelworkers international president Lynn R. Williams asking to join in contributing to Technology and Work Program (affiliated with University of Lowell, Lowell, MA), with attached proposal, April 18, 1991; letters from Local 5668 president (Ravenswood, W. Va.) and New York Guild Union Local 3 member re lock-out by Ravenswood Aluminum Corporation, March 23, 1992; Wall Street Journal newspaper clipping re efforts of union to reach out to white-collar workers, May 23, 1991; flyer announcing AFL-CIO president John Sweeney's attendance at rally in New York to demand that Merril Lynch, as top shareholder of Wheeling-Pitt Steel, to urge company to settle strike fairly, July 15, 1997; letter to Mazur from AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland detailing effort to support striking steelworkers at USX, August 8, 1986
  - United Synagogue of America, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    Press release from Local 153, Office & Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU), AFL-CIO, re strike against United Synagogue of America over employer demand to switch health plans, January 24, 1990; copy of information booklet about United Synagogue of America, listing presidents, officers
  - United Textile Workers, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    Memo to Mazur from ILGWU director of organization Joe Danahy re meeting with Vernon Mustard, president of United Textile Workers, and move of headquarters to Cherryhill, NJ, December 10, 1986
  - United Transportation Union, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    Letter from union president Fred Hardin to AFL-CIO secretary-treasurer Thomas Donahue, objecting to interference with UTU election, October 6, 1987
  - Usury, Bill, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    See also Leslie Fay Co. 1994 Letters from Mazur to Herb Fishgold and Bill Usury, president of labor-management consultants Bill Usury Associates, Inc., expressing outrage, shock, and disgust at failure to enforce labor-management cooperation agreement with Leslie Fay to preserve 600 jobs in the Wyoming Valley of Pennsylvania, May 3, 4, and 8, 1995; list of talking points with Usery, May 3
  - Uruguay Round (NAFTA)-Apparel and Textiles, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    Memo to Mazur from ILGWU research director Herman Starobin re GSP Decisions by USTR (United States Trade Representative Mickey Kantor), July 11, 1994; attached briefings, "Why Congress Should Not Rush to Vote on the Uruguay Round" and "The Uruguay Round on Apparel and Textiles"
  - Vickers, John, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    Letter to Mazur from John Vickers, retiring manager, ILGWU Texas-Oklahoma District Council, reminiscing about training institute, thanking him for years of leadership, December 23, 1994
  - Visions/Services for the Blind, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    Proposal to Mazur for pilot project by Visions/Services for the Blind and Visually Impared (merger of Vacations and Community Services for the Blind with Center for Independent Living) to assist retired union members, December 4, 1986
  - Voter Registration, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    List of election law provisions re voter registration, absentee voting, major party convention selection process, and election calendar by state, 1988; memo to Mazur re voter-registration plans for NYC mayoral campaign of David Dinkins, focusing on pro-Dinkins target groups (union membership, immigrants), March 17, 1989
  - Vyorst, Sidney, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    Letter to Vyorst from ILGWU exec vp Irwin Solomon refuting claim that Vyorst has a contract with ILGWU, asking for appointment to discuss matter, March 19, 1986; letters to Mazur from Vyorst quoting life insurance rates, 1984; letter to Mazur re contract, 1983
  - Wage-Hour Compliance, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    Draft of San Francisco, CA, Department of Labor press release re voluntary model agreement for apparel industry in Region 9, with cover note to Mazur from Max Zimny, n.d.; revised statement, July 22, 1994
  - Wall Street Journal, 1985-1990 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    See also Textile, Apparel, and Footwear Trade Act of 1990 Memo to Mazur re visit to ILGWU archives by Wall St. Journal reporter, July 23, 1986; newspaper clippings from Journal, some with cover memos to Mazur and other ILGWU officials re contents, 1985; letter to the editor from ILGWU research director Herman Starobin correcting factual errors in article re apparel trade legislation, with article attached, July 31, 1990; letter to Journal from ILGWU Political Department associate director David Wells responding to article by Arthur Schlesinger Jr. re electoral college system of presidential election, August 24, 1988
  - Washington State Labor Council, AFL-CIO, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    Letter to AFL-CIO International Union Political Action Departments asking for compilations of congressional voting records on issues of interest, May 8, 1987
  - Weiss, Ted (Congressional Campaign), 1992 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    Letter to Mazur from Weiss thanking him for contribution to congressional campaign
  - Western Union, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    Description of group mobilization "action hotline" mailgram services, faxed to Mazur by pro-union sales representative, April 9, 1990
  - White House, 1993-1995 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    Correspondence with Executive and congressional branches: faxed message from White House comparing President Clinton's budget proposal to Republican congressional proposal, vowing veto, May 19, 1995; Congressional Quarterly list of congressional committees and subcommittees, profiles of new Republican members; letter from Mazur to Labor Secretary Robert Reich, urging continued ban on industrial homework in women's apparel industry, with attached position paper crafted for ILGWU by Shea & Gardner, May 10, 1993; testimony on the World Trade Organization by Dr. Herman Starobin, research director, ILGWU, before the Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, June 17, 1994; statement by Evelyn Dubrow, vice president and legislative director, ILGWU, before the Subcommittee on Trade, re trade with China, August 4, 1994; letter to Mazur from Pres. Clinton acknowledging attendance at AFL-CIO convention, stating support for longstanding pro-labor legislation, November 22, 1995; letter to Mzur from Harold Ickes, deputy chief of staff, noting support by Clinton for increase in minimum wage, August 28, 1995; letter to Mazur from Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan re health care reform, status of Health Security Act, December 5, 1994; address by Moynihan to Democratic National Convention, with cover letter to Mazur, December 16, 1994; letters to Mazur from Vice President Al Gore (addressed to "UNITED"), Sen. Dick Gephart, Rep. Pat Schroeder (re opposition to Immigration in the National Interest Act: to limit the number of refuges we admit would be a "crime against humanity"), Rep. Charles Rangel (thanking him for campaign contribution), and Rep. Carolyn Maloney (re itinerant Hong Kong tailors using unfair sales tactics); letters to Mazur from Department of Labor re Women in Apprenticeship and Nontraditional Occupations Act, August 4, 1994, and rule change by Office of the American Workplace, December 5, 1995; NYS Department of Labor press release, "State Labor Commissioner Sweeney Urges Cooperation of U.S. Labor Secretary Reich: 'Meet Us Halfway' in fighting garment sweatshops," with attached letter, November 1, 1995; letter to U.S. Trade Representative Mickey Kantor from Authur Andersen & Co. supporting NAFTA, October 9, 1995; invitation to joint symposium by Departments of Labor and State, "Forced Labor: The Growing Tragedy of the Prostitution of Children," September 29, 1995
  - Women, 1986-1995 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    see also NYC – Commission on the Status of Women Letter to Mazur asking him to be keynote speaker at conference, "Women's Rights, Workers' Rights: Strengthening Women's Voices on the Job," cosponsored by the AFL-CIO, March 23, 1995; letter to Mazur from ILGWU Pacific Northwest District Council manager Katie Quan asking him to consider sending a delegation to the U.N. Conference on Women, to be held in Beijing, January 10, 1995; resolution re rights of women, submitted to international organization FITTVCC/ORI by ILGWU and ACTWU, May 18, 1992; letter from researcher for the New York Chinatown History Project, listing questions about ILGWU's role in organizing women and relationship with Local 23-25, May 30, 1990; newsletter, National Women's Law Center Update, Summer 1990; resolutions on women and labor by the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers Federation, April 1990 and April 1989; letter from National Women's Law Center re Supreme Court and women's rights, reviewing decisions on employment discrimination, abortion, November 12, 1986
  - Women's Garment Industry, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 41)
    ILGWU Research Department paper, "Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry," October 25, 1994
  - Women's Policy Research, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    "Women's Work, Economic Trends, and Policy Issues," by Heidi Hartman, director, Institute for Women's Policy Research, paper presented at Organizing and Representing Professional, Technical and Salaried Women, George Meany Labor Studies Center, Department of Professional Employees, AFL-CIO
  - Women's Wear Daily, 1986-1992 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    Talking points for interview, n.d.; draft and final version of letter to the editor from Mazur re inaccuracies of newspaper's report on Congressional Budget Office study of U.S. apparel industry, January 14, 1992; newspaper clippings
  - Work and Family (AFL-CIO), 1989-1991 (Box 22, Folder 44)
    Draft by ILGWU vp Susan Cowell and final letter from Mazur to AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland suggesting the creation of an Office of Work and Family within the AFL-CIO; reply from Kirkland rejecting idea, but noting that the area will be coordinated by one of his assistants; meeting agendas of AFL-CIO Work and Family Steering Committee, October 25, 1990 - March 5, 1991; NYS Department of Labor newsletter, NY Works, with article by Cowell, "Work and Family: A Labor Perspective," fall 1990; newspaper clippings
  - Work and Technology Institute, 1992-1994 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    Bylaws; list of Board of Directors; minutes of November 10, 1992, and May 5, 1993, Board meetings; list of 1993 objectives; conference announcement, "Integrating Technology and People in High Performance Work Systems," May 18-20, 1994; letter to Mazur announcing pilot program, "Labor Participation in Workplace Modernization," asking him to serve on advisory committee, November 29, 1994
  - Work in America Institute-Productivity Forum, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 46)
    Directory of members; brochures re schedule of events, Spring Roundtable, May 23-25, 1995, Manager's Network, site visits to Miller Brewing Co., Trenton, Ohio, May 11, and Saturn Corp., Spring Hill, TN; cover letter, August 28, 1995, describing attached reports, "Worker Representation and Participation Survey: Second Report on Findings," Freeman & Rogers, June 1, 1995, and "Human Resource Strategies and Contingent Workers: The Case of Safety and Health in the Petrochemical Industry," Kochan et al., Human Resource Management, spring 1994; "Worker Representation and Participation Survey: First Report on Findings," with cover letter, January 3, 1995
  - Work in America Institute-Productivity Forum, 1991-1994 (Box 22, Folder 47)
    Update memo to members of Productivity Forum Advisory Board, July 26, 1994; update on activities and services for 1991/92, July 1, 1992
  - Work in America Institute-Awards Ceremony (Sheinkman, Jack), 1992-1995 (Box 22, Folder 48)
    Speeches by Mazur honoring Jack Sheinkman, president ACTWU